American Hardware Corporation Records
© 2003 University of Connecticut
American Hardware Corporation Records.
undated, 1859-1953.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
American Hardware Corporation.
580 linear feet.
The records consist of financial records associated with the American Hardware Corporation of New Britain, Connecticut, its predecessor companies P. & F. Corbin and Russell & Erwin Manufacturing Company, and divisions Corbin Cabinet Lock Company and Corbin Screw Corporation.
MSS19950001
History
New Britain, Connecticut, established its dominance as the center of American hardware manufacturing as early as the late 1700s. Blacksmith shops provided a multitude of goods, including nails, hinges, locks and keys that were distributed by traveling peddlars to the farms and small towns of early America. By the mid-1800s entrepreneurs formed factories to better produce goods that were in increased demand.
The Russell & Erwin Manufacturing Company originated in 1839 when H.E. Russell, Cornelius B. Erwin, and Frederick T. Stanley formed a partnership to produce locks and builders' hardware, under the name of Stanley, Russell & Company. When Mr. Stanley withdrew from the partnership in 1840, Smith Matteson and John H. Bowen were added, changing the name of the company to Matteson, Russell & Company. In 1846, with the death of Mr. Matteson and the expiration of the partnership terms, the company's name changed to Russell & Erwin. In 1851 the partnership was reorganized as a joint stock company and was from that time known as Russell & Erwin Manufacturing Company, until its merger with P.& F. Corbin in 1902. Cornelius Erwin served as president of the company from 1851 until his death in 1885. The company is best known as the pioneer of the wrought steel lock industry.
P. & F. Corbin originated in 1849 when brothers Philip and Frank Corbin, and Edward Doen established the firm of Doen, Corbin & Co., to manufacture ox balls. The company's name changed to P. & F. Corbin in 1851. In the last half of the 19th century they broadened their products to include coffin trimmings, knobs, and stove handles. In 1868 they began specializing in the manufacture of builder's hardware and locks.
The American Hardware Corporation was formed in 1902 as a holding company through the merger of the Russell & Erwin Manufacturing Company and P. & F. Corbin, which were at that time separate and independent and rivals in the market for builders' hardware. At the time of the merger the two companies produced nearly one-half of the total hardware of this type in the United States. The two merged companies remained as distinct divisions of American Hardware Corporation and two other divisions - Corbin Cabinet Lock Company and the Corbin Screw Corporation - were added later.
Philip Corbin, president of P.& F. Corbin, served as American Hardware Corporation's first president until his death in 1910. Charles M. Jarvis served from 1910 to 1913, succeeded by Henry C.M. Thomson. In 1924 Mr. Thomson was succeeded by George T. Kimball.
Corbin Screw Corporation, a unit of the American Hardware Corporation, was formed in 1903 from the merger of the screw divisions of P. & F. Corbin and Russell & Erwin Manufacturing Company. It specialized in machine and other types of screws, bolts, chains, and escrutcheon pins.
Corbin Cabinet Lock Company was established in 1882 as a unit of P. & F. Corbin and became a division of the American Hardware Corporation in 1905. It produced cabinet hardware, padlocks, trunk locks, mail boxes, post office lock boxes, house letter boxes, straps, and brackets.
During both World Wars the companies manufactured such items as gun parts and hand grenades. In 1950 they employed 4,200 persons and occupied 2,255,912 square feet of floor space in three factories in New Britain.
In 1964 American Hardware was bought out by Emhart Corporation and in 1970 a new plant was built in Berlin. In 1989 Emhart was taken over by Black & Decker. Today, Corbin Russwin Architectural Hardware in Berlin, Connecticut, manufactures padlocks and is owned by a Swiss concern, which also owns Sargent Lock Company in New Haven, Connecticut.
Scope and Content
The collection consists exclusively of 577 volumes and one box of payroll lists and financial ledgers and journals relating to American Hardware Corporation and the predecessors and divisions associated with it, including Corbin Cabinet Lock Company, Russell & Erwin Manufacturing Company, Corbin Screw Corporation, and P.& F. Corbin.
Organization
The series are organized by company division.
Series I: American Hardware Corporation (1889-1953)
Series II: Corbin Cabinet Lock Company (1882-1939)
Series III: Russell & Erwin Manufacturing Company (1864-1935)
Series IV: Corbin Screw Corporation (1903-1935)
Series V: P. & F. Corbin (1859-1944)
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of Connecticut business records, including the Bristol Brass Company Records, the Emhart Corporation Records, the Farrel Company Records, the Holley Manufacturing Company Records, Sargent & Company Records, and Steele and Johnson Company Records. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Arrangement
The materials were sorted by division with the corporation, thereunder by type of item and then chronologically. Payroll lists are always the first type of documents, followed by various types of financial records.
Separated Material
906 financial ledgers were removed from the collection in August 2003. The ledgers consisted of financial records of American Hardware Corporation and its predecessor companies: P. & F. Corbin, Russel & Erwin Manufacturing Company, Corbin Cabinet Lock Company and Corbin Screw Corporation. These items were removed only after each volume was evaluated to determine whether its content justified the cost and labor of retention. All of the materials removed were solely "books of numbers", with virtually no historical information about the companies.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Organizations:
Family Names:
Places:
New Britain (Conn.)
Subjects:
Hardware industry--Connecticut; New Britain (Conn.)--Industries; P. & F. Corbin (New Britain, Conn.)
Document Types:
Administrative Records.; Financial Records.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Custodial History
This collection was held at the New Britain Industrial Museum before it arrived at the University of Connecticut Libraries in 1995.
Acquisition Information
The records were donated by the New Britain Industrial Museum in 1995.
Detailed Description/Box and Folder Listing
- Series I: American Hardware Corporation, 1889-1953
  - Payroll, 1907-1909 (Box 1)
  - Payroll, 1910 January - February (Box 2)
  - Payroll, 1910 May - June (Box 3)
  - Payroll, 1910 July - August (Box 4)
  - Payroll, 1910 September - October (Box 5)
  - Payroll, 1910 November - December (Box 6)
  - Payroll, 1911 January - February (Box 7)
  - Payroll, 1911 March - April (Box 8)
  - Payroll, 1911 May - June (Box 9)
  - Payroll, 1911 July - August (Box 10)
  - Payroll, 1911 September - October (Box 11)
  - Payroll, 1911 November - December (Box 12)
  - Payroll, 1912 January - February (Box 13)
  - Payroll, 1912 March - April (Box 14)
  - Payroll, 1912 May - June (Box 15)
  - Payroll, 1912 July - August (Box 16)
  - Payroll, 1912 September - October (Box 17)
  - Payroll, 1912 November - December (Box 18)
  - Payroll, 1913 January - February (Box 19)
  - Payroll, 1913 March - April (Box 20)
  - Payroll, 1913 May - June (Box 21)
  - Payroll, 1913 July (Box 22)
  - Payroll, 1913 August (Box 23)
  - Payroll, 1913 September (Box 24)
  - Payroll, 1913 October - December (Box 25)
  - Payroll, 1914 January (Box 26)
  - Payroll, 1914 January - February (Box 27)
  - Payroll, 1914 March - April (Box 28)
  - Payroll, 1914 May - June (Box 29)
  - Payroll, 1914 July - August (Box 30)
  - Payroll, 1914 September - October (Box 31)
  - Payroll, 1914 November (Box 32)
  - Payroll, 1914 December (Box 33)
  - Payroll, 1915 January - February (Box 34)
  - Payroll, 1915 March - April (Box 35)
  - Payroll, 1915 May (Box 36)
  - Payroll, 1915 June (Box 37)
  - Payroll (Change in Payroll), 1942-1950 (Box 38)
  - Payroll, 1947-1948 (Box 39)
  - Payroll, 1947-1948 (Box 40)
  - Payroll, 1947-1948 (Box 41)
  - Payroll, 1947-1948 (Box 42)
  - Payroll, 1948-1949 (Box 43)
  - Payroll, 1948-1949 (Box 44)
  - Payroll, 1948-1950 (Box 45)
  - Payroll, 1948-1950 (Box 46)
  - Payroll, 1949-1950 (Box 47)
  - Payroll, 1950 (Box 48)
  - Payroll, 1950-1951 (Box 49)
  - Payroll, 1950-1951 (Box 50)
  - Payroll, 1950-1952 (Box 51)
  - Payroll, 1951-1953 (Box 52)
  - Payroll, 1951 (Box 53)
  - Payroll, 1951-1952 (Box 54)
  - Payroll, 1953 (Box 55)
  - Payroll, 1953-1954 (Box 56)
  - Payroll, 1953-1954 (Box 57)
  - Payroll, 1953-1954 (Box 58)
  - Payroll, 1953-1954 (Box 59)
  - Employee wage records, 1951 (Box 60)
  - Cash book, 1902-1912 (Box 61)
  - Cash book, 1907-1909 (Box 62)
  - Cash book, 1913-1914 (Box 63)
  - Cash book, 1919 (Box 64)
  - Cash book, 1919 (Box 65)
  - Cash book, 1927-1933 (Box 66)
  - Transfer cash book, cash paid/received, 1913 (Box 67)
  - Transfer cash book, cash paid/received, 1916 (Box 68)
  - Transfer cash book, cash paid/received, 1919 (Box 69)
  - Transfer cash book, cash paid/received, 1919 (Box 70)
  - Transfer cash book, cash paid/received, 1919 (Box 71)
  - Transfer cash book, cash paid/received, 1924-1925 (Box 72)
  - Transfer cash book, cash paid/received, 1926-1927 (Box 73)
  - Transfer cash book, cash paid/received, 1926-1927 (Box 74)
  - Transfer cash book, cash paid, 1928 (Box 75)
  - Transfer cash book, cash paid, 1928 (Box 76)
  - Transfer cash book, cash paid, 1929 (Box 77)
  - Sectional cash disbursement, 1935 May - December (Box 78)
  - Sectional cash received, 1935 May (Box 79)
  - Sectional cash received, 1935 September (Box 80)
  - Sectional cash received, 1935 (Box 81)
  - Sectional cash received, 1935 October - 1936 July (Box 82)
  - Sectional cash received, undated (Box 83)
  - Cash sheets, 1912-1923, 1926-1928 (Box 84)
  - Bills/payable, 1925-1935 (Box 85)
  - Purchase ledger, 1924-1930 (Box 86)
  - Purchase ledger charges, 1931-1935 (Box 87)
  - Purchase ledger, undated (Box 88)
  - Purchase register, 1919 (Box 89)
  - General expense ledger, factory, 1921-1924 (Box 90)
  - Debit/credit, 1912 (Box 91)
  - Debit/credit, 1914 (Box 92)
  - Debit/credit, 1930-1933 (Box 93)
  - Debit/credit, 1934-1935 (Box 94)
  - Credit journal/railroad, 1910-1911 (Box 95)
  - Credit journal transfer/Chicago, 1916-1924 (Box 96)
  - Credit journal, 1917-1918 (Box 97)
  - Credit journal, 1932-1935 (Box 98)
  - Balance sheets, 1921-1935 (Box 99)
  - General ledger (combined ledger), 1936 (Box 100)
  - National trial balance, 1920-1921 (Box 101)
  - Trial balance, 1927-1929 (Box 102)
  - Trial balance, 1932-1952 (Box 103)
  - Record of approved vouchers, 1912-1934 (Box 104)
  - Record of approved vouchers, 1935-1936 (Box 105)
  - Statements P.O. & A-H, 1909-1911 (Box 106)
  - Statements I-Z, 1912-1913 (Box 107)
  - Daybook B, 1893-1894 (Box 108)
  - Daybook, undated (Box 109)
  - Old Customer's Journal, 1898 (Box 110)
  - Journal, 1903-1904 (Box 111)
  - Journal, 1912 (Box 112)
  - Journal, 1928-1930 (Box 113)
  - New York Journal, 1923-1934 (Box 114)
  - Ledger, 1894-1896 (Box 115)
  - Ledger, 1889-1892 (Box 116)
  - Ledger, 1899 (Box 117)
  - Ledger, 1902 (Box 118)
  - Ledger, 1904 (Box 119)
  - Ledger, 1906-1919 (Box 120)
  - Ledger, 1909 (Box 121)
  - Ledger, 1911-1912 (Box 122)
  - General financial ledger, 1912-1913 (Box 123)
  - General ledger, 1912-1947 (Box 124)
  - General ledger, 1915-1917 (Box 125)
  - Ledger, 1916-1947 (Box 126)
  - Ledger, 1922 (Box 127)
  - Ledger, 1923-1926 (Box 128)
  - Ledger, 1936 (Box 129)
  - Journal, 1892-1898 (Box 130)
  - Journal, 1933-1935 (Box 131)
  - Sub-ledger/Journal, 1895-1900 (Box 132)
  - Sub-ledger/Journal, 1912-1913 (Box 133)
  - Sub-ledger/Journal, 1912-1914 (Box 134)
  - Sub-ledger/Journal, 1912-1915 (Box 135)
  - Sub-ledger/Journal, 1912-1943 (Box 136)
  - Sub-ledger/Journal, 1914-1916 (Box 137)
  - Sub-ledger/Journal, 1917-1918 (Box 138)
  - Sub-ledger/Journal, 1919-1920 (Box 139)
  - Sub-ledger/Journal, 1921-1926 (Box 140)
  - Sub-ledger/Journal, 1927-1934 (Box 141)
  - Sub-ledger/Journal, 1933-1936 (Box 142)
  - Sub-ledger/Journal, 1935-1936 (Box 143)
  - Credit journal, New York, 1932-1935 (Box 144)
  - Miscellaneous sales, 1935 (Box 145)
  - Raw material ledger, 1951 (Box 146)
  - Third Liberty Bond book, 1918-1919 (Box 147)
  - Fourth Liberty Bond book, 1919 (Box 148)
  - Returned goods, 1930-1934 (Box 149)
  - Letters, 1901-1904 (Box 150)
  - Health Care Manual, undated (Box 151)
- Series II: Corbin Cabinet Lock Company, 1882-1939
  - Payroll, 1891-1893 (Box 152)
  - Payroll, 1901-1902 (Box 153)
  - Payroll, 1903 (Box 154)
  - Payroll, 1905 (Box 155)
  - Payroll, 1906 (Box 156)
  - Payroll, 1907 (Box 157)
  - Payroll, 1907 (Box 158)
  - Payroll, 1908 (Box 159)
  - Payroll, 1908 (Box 160)
  - Payroll, 1910 (Box 161)
  - Payroll, 1910 (Box 162)
  - Payroll, 1910 (Box 163)
  - Payroll, 1912 (Box 164)
  - Payroll, 1912 (Box 165)
  - Payroll, 1912 (Box 166)
  - Payroll, 1912 (Box 167)
  - Payroll, 1912 (Box 168)
  - Payroll, 1912 (Box 169)
  - Payroll, 1912 (Box 170)
  - Payroll, 1912 (Box 171)
  - Payroll, 1913 (Box 172)
  - Payroll, 1914 (Box 173)
  - Payroll, 1914 (Box 174)
  - Payroll, 1914 (Box 175)
  - Payroll, 1914 (Box 176)
  - Payroll, 1914 (Box 177)
  - Payroll, 1914 (Box 178)
  - Payroll, 1914 (Box 179)
  - Office payroll, 1915-1916 (Box 180)
  - Payroll, 1916 (Box 181)
  - Payroll, 1916 (Box 182)
  - Payroll, 1916 (Box 183)
  - Payroll, 1916 (Box 184)
  - Payroll, 1916 (Box 185)
  - Payroll, 1916 (Box 186)
  - Payroll, 1916 (Box 187)
  - Payroll, 1916 (Box 188)
  - Payroll, 1918 (Box 189)
  - Payroll, 1918 (Box 190)
  - Payroll, 1918 (Box 191)
  - Payroll, 1918 (Box 192)
  - Payroll, 1918 (Box 193)
  - Payroll, 1918 (Box 194)
  - Payroll, 1918 (Box 195)
  - Payroll, 1920 (Box 196)
  - Payroll, 1920 (Box 197)
  - Payroll, 1920 (Box 198)
  - Payroll, 1920 (Box 199)
  - Payroll, 1920 (Box 200)
  - Payroll, 1920 (Box 201)
  - Payroll, 1920 (Box 202)
  - Payroll, 1921 (Box 203)
  - Cashbook, 1888-1889 (Box 204)
  - Cashbook, 1889 (Box 205)
  - Cashbook, 1895-1897 (Box 206)
  - Cashbook, 1896 (Box 207)
  - Cashbook, 1897 (Box 208)
  - Cashbook, 1900 (Box 209)
  - Cashbook, 1900 (Box 210)
  - Cashbook, 1902 (Box 211)
  - Cashbook, 1904 (Box 212)
  - Cashbook, 1904 (Box 213)
  - Cashbook, 1908 (Box 214)
  - Cashbook, 1912 (Box 215)
  - Cashbook, 1914 (Box 216)
  - Cashbook, 1916 (Box 217)
  - Cashbook, 1918 (Box 218)
  - Cashbook, 1920-1921 (Box 219)
  - Cashbook, 1922-1923 (Box 220)
  - Cashbook, 1926-1927 (Box 221)
  - Cashbook, 1930-1931 (Box 222)
  - Cashbook, 1932-1934 (Box 223)
  - Cashbook, 1935 (Box 224)
  - Cashbook, New York 1899 (Box 225)
  - Petty cash, 1912-1917 (Box 226)
  - Petty cash, 1918 (Box 227)
  - Accounts payable, 1934-1935 (Box 228)
  - Bill book, 1899-1901 (Box 229)
  - Bill book, 1902-1904 (Box 230)
  - Bill book, 1905-1907 (Box 231)
  - Bill book, 1906-1909 (Box 232)
  - Bill book, 1911-1914 (Box 233)
  - Purchase ledger, 1890 (Box 234)
  - Purchase ledger, 1894 (Box 235)
  - Purchase ledger, 1898 (Box 236)
  - Purchase ledger, 1899 (Box 237)
  - Purchase ledger, 1900 (Box 238)
  - Purchase ledger, 1902 (Box 239)
  - Purchase ledger, 1904 (Box 240)
  - Purchase ledger, 1906 (Box 241)
  - Purchase ledger, 1910 (Box 242)
  - Purchase ledger, 1912 (Box 243)
  - Purchase ledger, 1914 (Box 244)
  - Debit/credit journal, 1893-1894 (Box 245)
  - Debit/credit journal, 1895 (Box 246)
  - Debit/credit journal, 1896 (Box 247)
  - Debit/credit journal, 1897 (Box 248)
  - Debit/credit journal, 1897 (Box 249)
  - Debit/credit journal, 1898 (Box 250)
  - Debit/credit journal, 1898 (Box 251)
  - Debit/credit journal, 1900 (Box 252)
  - Debit/credit journal, 1902 (Box 253)
  - Debit/credit journal, 1902 (Box 254)
  - Debit/credit journal, 1902 (Box 255)
  - Debit/credit journal, 1904 (Box 256)
  - Debit/credit journal, 1904 (Box 257)
  - Debit/credit journal, 1906 (Box 258)
  - Debit/credit journal, 1908 (Box 259)
  - Debit/credit journal, 1910 (Box 260)
  - Debit/credit journal, 1912 (Box 261)
  - Debit/credit journal, 1915-1924 (Box 262)
  - Debit/credit journal, 1932-1934 (Box 263)
  - New York credit journal, 1936-1939 (Box 264)
  - Chicago credit journal, 1936-1939 (Box 265)
  - Credits, 1935-1936 (Box 266)
  - Credit memoranda, 1936-1937 (Box 267)
  - Accounts payable, 1931-1933 (Box 268)
  - Trial balance, 1908-1909 (Box 269)
  - Sales book, 1888-1890 (Box 270)
  - Sales book, 1890-1895 (Box 271)
  - Proof book, sales ledger, 1892 (Box 272)
  - Sales records, 1888-1932 (Box 273)
  - Monthly statements, 1890 (Box 274)
  - Monthly statements, 1894 (Box 275)
  - Monthly statements, 1895 (Box 276)
  - Monthly statements, 1896 (Box 277)
  - Monthly statements, 1900-1903 (Box 278)
  - Monthly statements, 1900-1903 (Box 279)
  - Monthly statements, 1915 (Box 280)
  - Ledger, 1882-1892 (Box 280a)
  - Ledger, 1889 (Box 280b)
  - Ledger, 1896-1897 (Box 280c)
  - General ledger, 1897 (Box 281)
  - Ledger, 1898-1891 (Box 282)
  - General ledger, 1899 (Box 283)
  - General ledger, 1900 (Box 284)
  - General ledger, 1904 (Box 285)
  - General ledger, 1906 (Box 286)
  - General ledger, 1908 (Box 287)
  - General ledger, 1910 (Box 288)
  - General ledger, 1911-1912 (Box 289)
  - Journal, 1912-1914 (Box 290)
  - General ledger, 1914 (Box 291)
  - Journal, 1914 (Box 292)
  - Journal, 1915-1916 (Box 293)
  - General ledger, 1916 (Box 294)
  - General ledger, 1918 (Box 295)
  - General ledger, 1920 (Box 296)
  - General ledger, 1922-1930 (Box 297)
  - Journal, 1923-1934 (Box 298)
  - General ledger, 1924 (Box 299)
  - Journal, 1924-1928 (Box 300)
  - Ledger, 1924-1929 (Box 300a)
  - General ledger, 1930 (Box 301)
  - General ledger, 1932 (Box 302)
  - General ledger, 1934 (Box 303)
  - Export journal, 1917-1926 (Box 304)
  - Export journal, 1933-1935 (Box 305)
  - Allowances/distribution, 1931-1932 (Box 306)
  - Checks, 1890-1892 (Box 307)
  - Checkbook, 1909 (Box 308)
  - Post office reports, 1903-1907 (Box 309)
  - List of customers, 1897 (Box 310)
  - List of customers, 1897 (Box 311)
  - Tools, fixtures, machinery, merchandise, 1895 (Box 312)
- Series III: Russell & Erwin Manufacturing Company, 1864-1935
  - Cashbook, 1864-1868 (Box 313)
  - Cashbook, 1880-1883 (Box 314)
  - New York cash receipts, 1923-1929 (Box 315)
  - New York cash receipts, 1930-1932 (Box 316)
  - Cash receipts, 1920-1922 (Box 317)
  - Cash receipts, 1922-1926 (Box 318)
  - Cash receipts, 1927 (Box 319)
  - Cash receipts, 1928-1930 (Box 320)
  - Cash receipts, 1931 (Box 321)
  - Cash receipts, 1932-1934 (Box 322)
  - Cash receipts, 1933 (Box 323)
  - Cash disbursements, 1921-1926 (Box 324)
  - Cash disbursements, 1921-1929 (Box 325)
  - Cash disbursements, 1928-1931 (Box 326)
  - Cash disbursements, 1932-1934 (Box 327)
  - Cash disbursements, 1935 (Box 328)
  - Cash disbursements, 1935 (Box 329)
  - Petty cash, 1908-1925 (Box 330)
  - Transfer petty cash, 1925-1933 (Box 331)
  - Notes and bills receivable, 1914-1932 (Box 332)
  - Return purchase, 1932-1934 (Box 333)
  - Accounts payable, 1927 (Box 334)
  - Accounts payable, 1928 (Box 335)
  - Accounts payable (New York), 1929 (Box 336)
  - Accounts payable, 1930 (Box 337)
  - Accounts payable, 1930 (Box 338)
  - Accounts payable, 1931 (Box 339)
  - Accounts payable, 1935 (Box 340)
  - Trial balance, 1903 (Box 341)
  - Trial balance (New York), 1921-1925 (Box 342)
  - New York approved vouchers, 1910-1913 (Box 343)
  - New York approved vouchers, 1920 (Box 344)
  - Return sales, 1898-1899 (Box 345)
  - Daybook, 1891-1893 (Box 346)
  - Daybook, 1893-1895 (Box 347)
  - Daybook, 1896-1897 (Box 348)
  - Invoice book, 1898-1899 (Box 349)
  - Invoice book, 1900 (Box 350)
  - Invoice book, 1903-1905 (Box 351)
  - Invoice book, 1906-1908 (Box 352)
  - Receipts, 1927 (Box 353)
  - General ledger, 1898-1902 (Box 354)
  - General ledger, 1923-1926 (Box 355)
  - General ledger, 1934 (Box 356)
  - General ledger, 1935 (Box 357)
  - New Britain general ledger, 1932 (Box 358)
  - New York general ledger, 1933 (Box 359)
  - Ledger, 1918-1921 (Box 360)
  - Ledger, 1927-1930 (Box 361)
  - Journal, 1888-1891 (Box 362)
  - Journal, 1891-1893 (Box 363)
  - Journal, 1895-1896 (Box 364)
  - New Britain journal, 1915-1917 (Box 365)
  - New York journal, 1915-1917 (Box 366)
  - C.O.D. register, 1935 (Box 367)
  - Freight record, 1932-1934 (Box 368)
  - Returns/allowances, 1900-1901 (Box 370)
  - New York stock, 1930-1935 (Box 371)
  - Factory rebates, 1903 (Box 372)
  - Distribution, 1931 (Box 373)
  - "Working sheets" (financial summaries), 1921-1935 (Box 535)
- Series IV: Corbin Screw Corporation, 1903-1935
  - Cash received, 1924-1927 (Box 374)
  - Cashbook, 1914-1920 (Box 375)
  - Cash paid, 1914-1923 (Box 376)
  - Cash paid, 1924-1933 (Box 377)
  - Chicago cashbook, 1913 (Box 378)
  - New York cashbook, 1929-1933 (Box 379)
  - Philadelphia cashbook, 1921-1933 (Box 380)
  - Purchase ledger, 1903 (Box 381)
  - Purchase ledger, 1932 (Box 382)
  - New York credit journal, 1913-1915 (Box 383)
  - Credit journal, 1929-1934 (Box 384)
  - Philadelphia credit, 1921-1934 (Box 385)
  - Credit book, 1934-1935 (Box 386)
  - Chicago credit journal, 1913-1915 (Box 387)
  - New York debit/credit journal, 1914-1924 (Box 388)
  - General ledger, 1912-1913 (Box 389)
  - General ledger, 1913-1925 (Box 390)
  - General ledger, 1925-1933 (Box 391)
  - Philadelphia general ledger, 1921-1934 (Box 392)
  - Accounts payable, 1933-1934 (Box 393)
  - Accounts payable, 1935 (Box 394)
  - New York trial balance, 1914-1930 (Box 395)
  - Trial balance, 1916 (Box 396)
  - Trial balance, 1928-1935 (Box 397)
  - Bill book, 1918-1935 (Box 398)
- Series V: P. & F. Corbin, 1859-1944
  - Payroll, 1871-1872 (Box 399)
  - Payroll, 1881-1883 (Box 400)
  - Payroll, 1888-1889 (Box 401)
  - Payroll, 1890-1891 (Box 402)
  - Payroll, 1891 (Box 403)
  - Payroll, 1892-1893 (Box 404)
  - Payroll, 1893-1894 (Box 405)
  - Payroll, 1894-1895 (Box 406)
  - Payroll, 1895-1896 (Box 407)
  - Payroll, 1896-1897 (Box 408)
  - Payroll, 1897-1898 (Box 409)
  - Payroll, 1898-1899 (Box 410)
  - Payroll, 1900 (Box 411)
  - Payroll, 1901 (Box 412)
  - Payroll, 1901-1902 (Box 413)
  - Payroll, 1902-1903 (Box 414)
  - Payroll, 1903 (Box 415)
  - Payroll, 1903 (Box 416)
  - Payroll, 1904 (Box 417)
  - Payroll, 1904 (Box 418)
  - Payroll, 1905 (Box 419)
  - Payroll, 1905 (Box 420)
  - Payroll, 1905 (Box 421)
  - Payroll, 1905 (Box 422)
  - Payroll, 1906 (Box 423)
  - Payroll, 1906 (Box 424)
  - Payroll, 1906 (Box 425)
  - Payroll, 1906 (Box 426)
  - Payroll, 1907 (Box 427)
  - Payroll, 1907 (Box 428)
  - Payroll, 1907 (Box 429)
  - Payroll, 1907 (Box 430)
  - Payroll, 1908 (Box 431)
  - Payroll, 1908 (Box 432)
  - Payroll, 1908 (Box 433)
  - Payroll, 1908 (Box 434)
  - Payroll, 1909 (Box 435)
  - Payroll, 1909 (Box 436)
  - Payroll, 1909 (Box 437)
  - Payroll, 1909 (Box 438)
  - Payroll, 1910 (Box 439)
  - Payroll, 1910 (Box 440)
  - Payroll, 1910 (Box 441)
  - Payroll, 1911 (Box 442)
  - Payroll, 1911 (Box 443)
  - Payroll, 1911 (Box 444)
  - Payroll, 1912 (Box 445)
  - Payroll, 1912 (Box 446)
  - Payroll, 1912 (Box 447)
  - Payroll, 1912 (Box 448)
  - Payroll lists, 1912 (Box 534:2)
  - Payroll, 1913 (Box 449)
  - Payroll, 1913 (Box 450)
  - Payroll, 1913 (Box 451)
  - Payroll, 1914 (Box 452)
  - Payroll, 1914 (Box 453)
  - Payroll, 1914 (Box 454)
  - Payroll, 1914 (Box 455)
  - Payroll, 1914 (Box 456)
  - Payroll, 1914 (Box 457)
  - Payroll, 1914 (Box 458)
  - Payroll, New York, 1917 (Box 459)